<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Western Carolina University (WCU) Program for the Study of Developed Shorelines</origin>
        <origin>American Shore and Beach Preservation Association (ASBPA)</origin>
        <origin>U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE) Regional Sediment Management Program</origin>
        <origin>Department of Commerce (DOC), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) National Ocean Service (NOS), National Centers for Coastal Ocean Science (NCCOS)</origin>
        <origin>Department of Commerce (DOC), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) National Ocean Service (NOS), Office for Coastal Management (OCM)</origin>
        <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
        <title>Beach_Nourishment</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>ftp://ftp.coast.noaa.gov/pub/MSP/ORT/</onlink>
        <onlink>https://coast.noaa.gov/arcgis/rest/services/OceanReportingTool</onlink>
        <onlink>https://coast.noaa.gov/</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Beach Nourishment projects occur throughout coastal states in the United States. These projects can be privately, federally or state funded. Material used in nourishment comes from a variety of sources (inland sources, dredged navigational channels or offshore sites). This GIS dataset combines historical data compiled in the Western Carolina University Beach Nourishment Viewer database, as well as the National Beach Nourishment Database generated by the American Shore and Beach Preservation Association. The data contain attribute information on the general location of sand placement, primary funding source and funding type, volume of sediment emplacement (in cubic yards), length of beach nourished (in feet) and cost and inflated cost for over 2,000 beach nourishment episodes dating back to 1923.</abstract>
      <purpose>To support coastal and ocean planning and other activities pursuant to the Energy Policy Act, Coastal Zone Management Act, Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, National Environmental Policy Act, Rivers and Harbors Act and the Submerged Lands Act.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>Unknown</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>As needed</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-165.431308</westbc>
        <eastbc>-69.932613</eastbc>
        <northbc>64.497700</northbc>
        <southbc>20.907669</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>marine cadastre, marine spatial planning, environmental, oceans, environment, farming, planningCadastre, United States, national, alternative energy planning, coastal energy planning, environmental energy planning, ocean energy planning, offshore energy planning, renewable energy planning, seafloor sediment, sand resources, management, natural resources</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>United States, Atlantic, Pacific, national</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>These data are intended for coastal and ocean use planning. Not for navigation.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Office for Coastal Management</cntorg>
          <cntper>MarineCadastre.gov Data Steward</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>MarineCadastre.gov Data Steward</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>2234 South Hobson Avenue</address>
          <city>Charleston</city>
          <state>SC</state>
          <postal>29405-2413</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>843.740.1202</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>coastal.info@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.1.7333</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>The attributes in this dataset are believed to be accurate.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>These data are believed to be logically consistent. Geometry is topologically clean.</logic>
    <complete>Spatial and attribute properties are believed to be complete, although attribute information has been simplified. Geometric thresholds from original data are preserved. No tests have been completed for exhaustiveness.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>Maximum scale of intended use is 1:80,000.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Western Carolina University (WCU) Program for the Study of Developed Shorelines</origin>
            <origin>American Shore and Beach Preservation Association (ASBPA) National Beach Nourishment Database</origin>
            <pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
            <title>Beach Nourishment Locations</title>
            <onlink>http://beachnourishment.wcu.edu/</onlink>
            <onlink>https://gim2.aptim.com/ASBPANationwideRenourishment/</onlink>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>online</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>201805</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Unknown</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Beach nourishment locations and associated attributes</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>(1) ‘Master’ Database was downloaded from Western Carolina University Program for the Study of Developed Shorelines in Excel format.
(2) These data were compared with the data from the online National Beach Nourishment Database (NBND): https://gim2.aptim.com/ASBPANationwideRenourishment/
(3) 2016-2018 data that were not contained in the WCU database were collected from the NBND
(4) These data were then combined into one resulting point data Excel spreadsheet and imported into ArcGIS to create the resulting database
</procdesc>
        <procdate>201805</procdate>
        <proccont>
          <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
              <cntorg>NOAA NCCOS Coastal Aquaculture Siting and Sustainability (CASS)</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
              <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
              <address>101 Pivers Island Road</address>
              <city>Beaufort</city>
              <state>NC</state>
              <postal>28516</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>252.728.8797</cntvoice>
          </cntinfo>
        </proccont>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>2189</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 World Mercator</mapprojn>
          <mercator>
            <stdparll>0.0</stdparll>
            <longcm>0.0</longcm>
            <feast>0.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </mercator>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.0001</absres>
            <ordres>0.0001</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Beach_Nourishment</enttypl>
        <enttypd>A database of beach nourishment locations and associated information.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>NOAA Office for Coastal Management</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Beach_Loca</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>A beach, park, island, community or other commonly-recognized jurisdictional designation encompassing and identifying the geographic boundary and/or extent of shoreline upon which sediment has been emplaced.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Alphanumeric text defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>State</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State in which beach nourishment project was completed.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Alphanumeric text defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Latitude</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Latitude for point feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Longitude</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Longitude for point feature.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Justificat</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>the primary reason why a beach was renourished.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Bypass</edomv>
            <edomvd>Artificially moving sand from an updrift beach to a downdrift beach in order to bypass a natural or artificial obstruction such as an inlet or jetty.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Coastal Impact Assistance Program</edomv>
            <edomvd>Federal grant funds derived from federal offshore lease revenues to the oil-producing states of Alabama, Alaska, California, Louisiana, Mississippi and Texas for conservation, protection, or restoration of coastal areas.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Demonstration</edomv>
            <edomvd>A U.S. Army Corps of Engineers experimental effort that places sand in an offshore location, rather than directly on a beach.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Ecosystem Restoration</edomv>
            <edomvd>An effort to reestablish or improve coastal habitat that has been degraded or damaged by natural or human activities.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Emergency</edomv>
            <edomvd>Designed to create an artificial beach berm in order to provide a minimum level of protection to vulnerable coastal development, usually post-storm. All Federal nourishment episodes classified as Emergency are funded through FEMA or the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Emergency Dune</edomv>
            <edomvd>Designed to construct an artificial dune in order to provide a minimum level of protection to vulnerable coastal development, usually post-storm.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Navigation</edomv>
            <edomvd>Sediment (known as dredge spoil) resulting from a navigation-related dredging effort is placed on a beach rather than dumped offshore or in an upland location.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Section 111</edomv>
            <edomvd>Mitigation of shoreline damages attributable to Federal navigation structures (jetties).</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Shore Protection</edomv>
            <edomvd>Nourishment episodes undertaken for the primary purpose of reducing storm-related damage to static human economic development placed behind dynamic shorelines.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>WCU</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Length__ft</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The linear distance of shoreline upon which sediment has been emplaced, measured in feet.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers calculated for features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Volume__CY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Volume is the quantity of sand emplaced on a beach during a beach nourishment episode measured in cubic yards.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers calculated for features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Nominal_Co</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The cost (amount spent) on a beach nourishment episode in the year the episode was completed, measured in US dollars.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Alphanumeric text defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Year</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The year in which a nourishment episode was completed. Beach nourishment typically commences in the late fall/early winter due to environmental and ecological concerns. As a result, nourishment episodes usually begin at the end of the year and wrap-up early the next year.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>WCU</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Alphanumeric text defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Office for Coastal Management</cntorg>
          <cntper>MarineCadastre.gov Data Steward</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>MarineCadastre.gov Data Steward</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>2234 South Hobson Avenue</address>
          <city>Charleston</city>
          <state>SC</state>
          <postal>29405-2413</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>843.740.1202</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>coastal.info@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>NOAA makes no warranties or representations whatsoever regarding the availability, quality, accuracy, content, completeness or suitability for the user's needs of such information. The services, information, and data made available on the Marine Cadastre web site are provided "as is" without warranties of any kind. These data are intended for coastal and ocean use planning. Not for navigation. http://www.marinecadastre.gov/about/disclaimer.html</distliab>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20180626</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Office for Coastal Management</cntorg>
          <cntper>MarineCadastre.gov Data Steward</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>MarineCadastre.gov Data Steward</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>2234 South Hobson Avenue</address>
          <city>Charleston</city>
          <state>SC</state>
          <postal>29405-2413</postal>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>843.740.1202</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>coastal.info@noaa.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>